Register of the Committee for a Community of Democracies--USA records
Hoover Institution Archives
Committee for a Community of Democracies--USA records
1979-1992
Committee for a Community of Democracies--USA.
92026
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
20 manuscript boxes (8.1 linear feet)
The papers include correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting minutes, agendas, conference proceedings, financial records, and sound recordings related to efforts of the CCD-USA to promote international cooperation and to fundraising efforts. Includes some records of the International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD).
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection
James Robert Huntley papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Historical Note
The United States division of the Committee for a Community of Democracies (CCD-USA), a private nonprofit organization to promote international cooperation among democratic countries, was incorporated in July 1983. The goal of the committee was to study relationships between democratic nations and the ways in which those relationships could be strengthened.
The concept of the Committees for a Community of Democracies was envisioned in 1979 when a small group started meeting at the Atlantic Council of the United States. In 1982, groups in Washington and London organized an international meeting, where a representative from Australia suggested that the CCD widen the scope of its objectives to include closer cooperation among democracies.
In 1983, the CCD-USA sent a delegation to the Conference on Parliamentary Democracy held in Strasbourg, and soon after, the CCD-USA received a grant from the National Endowment for Democracy (NED) to hold a preparatory meeting (called PREFACE) on democratic solidarity at the Wingspread Conference Center in Wisconsin, which was attended by 36 participants from 26 countries. The attendants of this meeting implemented a resolution to create the International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD), a group which would include all of the attendants of the PREFACE meeting, as well as all members of local CCDs. At this meeting, proposals were also submitted for the creation of the Association for Democracies (to provide a forum or meeting place for CCD), the International Institute for Democracy (created as a resource for democracies in need of help), and a caucus of democracies in the United Nations. Participants at PREFACE envisioned a program of seminars, leading to an all-democracies conference.
In December 1988, the All-Democracies Conference was held at the Gerald R. Ford Library in Ann Arbor, Michigan. The conference boasted 68 representatives from 44 democracies, with former United States presidents Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter serving as co-hosts of the event.
In 1992, the Association to Unite the Democracies embarked on the Next Century Initiative (NCI), which was based on the ideas of the Committees for a Community of Democracies and involved many of its early members. The NCI became incorporated as a separate group, eventually becoming the Council for a Community of Democracies.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the work of the United States division of the Committee for a Community of Democracies (CCD-USA) through correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting minutes, agendas, conference proceedings, financial records, and sound recordings related to efforts of the CCD-USA to promote international cooperation. The collection includes some records of the International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD), an administrative body for CCDs around the world, with CCD-USA serving as its operational center.
The collection is arranged based on original headings and a numbering scheme attached to those headings. Although series names (with the exclusion of the sound recordings) were taken from ten headings found within the collection, several of the original headings were changed to clarify series contents. Folders without headings were integrated into the existing system.
The CCD-USA sought to establish and study relationships between democratic nations. The Administrative file and Organization and administration file contain background information on the work of the CCD-USA, as well as chronological files of correspondence for administrators of the CCD-USA, meeting minutes, correspondence, and membership lists. Also included are documents dating from the early years of the CCD and the CCD-USA, including materials from the first international meeting in London, and letters of Ronald Reagan and George Shultz.
The National Endowment for Democracy (NED) was the primary source of funding for the CCD-USA. The National Endowment for Democracy (NED) file includes grants and quarterly progress reports that the CCD-USA submitted to NED detailing project goals and outcomes. Files on other funders can be found in the Funding sources and activities file.
The CCD-USA received a grant from the National Endowment for Democracy (NED) to hold a preparatory meeting (called PREFACE) on democratic solidarity at the Wingspread Conference Center in Wisconsin. The PREFACE conference at Wingspread, post-conference action file contains correspondence, proposals, and reports on projects envisioned at that conference, such as the regional seminars, the All-Democracies Conference, the International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD), and the Association of Democracies. The Projects file details the organization of these meetings, including PREFACE, and contains material on groups proposed during these conferences, such as the International Institute for Democracy. The Policy matters file contains proposals for these projects, as well as policy meeting minutes.
Media coverage of the CCD-USA is documented in the Public relations and the media file through clippings, correspondence, and newsletters. The Name lists and individual file includes correspondence between CCD-USA members and people around the world.
The Sound recordings contain speeches of former presidents Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter given at the All-Democracies Conference.
International Committee for a Community of Democracies.; Democracy.; International cooperation.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Relations.
- Administrative file, 1979-1992 (Box 1-7)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes chronological files of correspondence for administrators of the CCD-USA, meeting minutes, correspondence, and membership lists. Includes early material for CCD and CCD-USA, such as concept papers. Originally titled "Record Material."
  - General, 1988 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Accountants' financial statements for 1985 and 1986 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Activities projection for 1987 to 1991 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Background information, 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Background pamphlets, 1982, undated (Folder 1: 5)
  - Background paper, 1985 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Biographical material on members, 1986-1988 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Board affairs, 1984-1989 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Center for Democracy, circa 1986 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Chronological files of members
    Mainly correspondence
    - De Palma, Samuel
      - 1984 (Folder 1: 10)
      - 1985 (Folder 1: 11)
      - 1986 (Folder 1: 12)
      - 1987 (Folder 1: 13-14)
      - 1988 (Folder 2: 1-2)
      - 1989 (Folder 2: 3-4)
      - 1990 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Foulon, Robert
      - 1985 (Folder 2: 6-7)
      - 1986 (Folder 2: 8-9)
      - 1987 (Folder 2: 10-11)
      - 1988 (Folder 2: 12-13)
      - 1989 (Folder 2: 14-15)
      - 1990 (Folder 2: 16)
    - Popper, David
      - 1986 (Folder 2: 17)
      - 1987 (Folder 2: 18-19)
    - Spear, Moncrieff J.
      - 1989 (Folder 2: 20)
      - 1990 (Folder 2: 21)
      - 1991 (Folder 2: 22)
    - Tanguy, Charles R.
      - 1984 (Folder 2: 23)
      - 1985 (Folder 3: 1)
      - 1986 (Folder 3: 2-3)
      - 1987 (Folder 3: 4-5)
      - 1988 (Folder 3: 6-7)
      - 1989 (Folder 3: 8-9)
      - 1990 (Folder 3: 10-11)
      - 1991 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Concept papers, 1979-1984 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1986 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Congress, 1991-1992 (Folder 4: 3)
    - International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD), 1987-1988, 1992 (Folder 4: 4-6)
    - Local chapters, members, association and advisory council, 1984-1989 (Folder 4: 7-11)
    - Overseas CCDs and contacts, 1984-1986 (Folder 4: 12-13)
    - Reagan, Ronald, 1985, 1988 (Folder 4: 14)
    - Shultz, George, 1987 (Folder 4: 15)
    - United States agencies, 1991-1992 (Folder 4: 16)
    - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1991 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Directory of CCD-USA, 1983 (Folder 4: 18)
    Includes correspondence
  - Inventory of material, 1987-1989 (Folder 4: 19)
  - List of cooperating organizations and correspondence, 1984-1985 (Folder 4: 20)
  - London Conference, 1981-1982 (Folder 4: 21-22)
    General note
    First international conference of the CCD
  - Meeting with John Whitehead, 1986 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Meeting minutes
    - Board of Directors and Executive Committee
      - 1984-1985 (Folder 4: 24)
      - 1986-1987 (Folder 5: 1-4)
      - 1988-1989 (Folder 5: 5-6)
    - Chapter meetings, 1984-1986 (Folder 5: 7-8)
    - Minute book, 1983-1991 (Folder 5: 9-10)
  - Membership lists, 1986-1989, undated (Folder 6: 1-4)
  - Memoranda of conversations, 1986-1987 (Folder 6: 5-6)
    Includes discussion of the European Regional Seminar
  - Organization, 1981-1983 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Pending file, 1990 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Poppers-Stedman report on networking in Latin American and the Caribbean, 1987-1988 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Project description for developing solidarity among democracies, 1984 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Report to the president, 1987 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Statement on CCD-USA and public diplomacy, 1987 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Washington, D.C. section, CCD (DC)
    - Agendas, 1982-1987 (Folder 6: 13-14)
    - Executive Group meetings, 1982-1984 (Folder 6: 15)
    - Meeting minutes, 1986-1987 (Folder 6: 16)
    - Meeting reports, 1981-1986 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Working Group meetings
    - 1985 (Folder 6: 18)
    - 1986 (Folder 7: 1)
    - 1987 (Folder 7: 2)
- Organization and administration file, 1982-1992 (Box 7)
  Includes articles of incorporation and bylaws, financial documents, correspondence, and meeting minutes.
  - Articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1983-1992 (Folder 7: 3-5)
  - Board of Directors and Advisory Council, 1991 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Budget, 1987 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Candidates for Board of Directors and Advisory Council, 1987 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Communications proposals, 1987 (Folder 7: 9)
  - Continental federal accounts, bills and receipts, 1985-1986 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Contract with Charles Tanguy, 1986 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Coordination and action plan, 1987 (Folder 7: 12)
  - New members of the Advisory Council and Board of Directors, 1986 (Folder 7: 13)
  - New and potential members, undated (Folder 7: 14)
  - Support group for CCD-USA, 1986 (Folder 7: 15)
- National Endowment for Democracy (NED), 1984-1989 (Box 7-8)
  Includes quarterly progress reports from CCD-USA to NED and grant proposals, requests, and agreements.
  - General, 1985-1989 (Folder 7: 16-21)
  - Conference on Democracy, 1987 (Folder 7: 22)
    Sponsored by the National Endowment for Democracy
  - Grant agreements, 1985-1989 (Folder 7: 23-25)
  - Grant agreements (Contd.), 1985-1989 (Folder 8: 1-4)
  - Grant proposals, 1984-1985 (Folder 8: 5-7)
  - Grant requests, 1986-1989 (Folder 8: 8-11)
  - Proposal for grant renewal, 1985 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Quarterly progress reports from CCD-USA to NED, 1984-1989 (Folder 8: 13-16)
- Projects file, 1982-1992 (Box 8-13)
  Includes correspondence, memorandum, and reports concerning conferences and seminars held by the CCD-USA, correspondence with members of congressional committees, grant proposals, and materials on the International Institute for Democracy.
  - African Regional Seminar, 1987 (Folder 8: 17)
    See also Name lists and individual file
  - Agency for International Development (AID) Latin American-Caribbean Seminar grant and correspondence, 1986 (Folder 8: 18)
  - All-Democracies Conference
    - General, 1986-1987 (Folder 8: 19-20)
    - General (Contd.), 1986-1987 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Letters to Ronald Reagan and others, 1988 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Overview, 1986 (Folder 9: 3)
    - Post-conference materials
      - Correspondence with Ronald Reagan, Oscar Arias, and others, 1989 (Folder 9: 4)
      - Distribution lists for papers, 1989 (Folder 9: 5)
      - Replies to circular letters to local ambassadors, 1988-1989 (Folder 9: 6)
      - Report, 1988 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Asia-Pacific Regional Seminar
    - General, 1986-1987 (Folder 9: 8)
    - Cables, 1986 (Folder 9: 9)
    - Correspondence, participants, and agendas, 1986 (Folder 9: 10)
    - Seminar papers, 1986 (Folder 9: 11)
    - Telexes, 1986 (Folder 9: 12)
  - Association of Democracies, 1987-1990 (Folder 9: 13-15)
  - Bhutto Initiative, 1989-1990 (Folder 9: 16-17)
  - Bicentennial Commission, 1986-1987 (Folder 9: 18)
  - Bicentennial of U.S. Constitution
    - Grant proposal, 1986 (Folder 10: 1)
    - James F. Byrnes Center, 1986 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Bush-Mitterand Joint Statement, 1989 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Center for National Policy, 1986-1988 (Folder 10: 4-6)
  - Correspondence with congressional committees, 1986-1992 (Folder 10: 7-11)
  - Council of Europe, 1987 (Folder 10: 12)
  - European Regional Seminar, 1985-1989 (Folder 10: 13-15)
  - First World Congress on Democracy, 1990 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Foreign Policy Association conference, 1987 (Folder 10: 17)
  - Former members of Congress, 1983-1987 (Folder 10: 18)
  - International Citizens Network, 1989 (Folder 10: 19)
  - International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD)
    - General, 1987 (Folder 10: 20)
    - Book on democracy, correspondence, 1988-1989 (Folder 10: 21)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Folder 11: 1)
    - Replies to questionnaire on ICCD charter, 1987 (Folder 11: 2)
  - International directory, 1991 (Folder 11: 3)
  - International Institute for Democracy, 1986-1992 (Folder 11: 4-8)
  - International Institute for Democracy, experts workshop
    - General, 1986-1987 (Folder 11: 9-10)
    - Proceedings, 1987 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Substantive papers, 1985-1987 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Labor Desk, 1982-1986 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Latin American-Caribbean Regional Seminar
    - General, 1986-1987 (Folder 12: 2)
    - Cables, 1986 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Correspondence, participants, and agenda, 1985-1986 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Liberal International (London), 1985-1986 (Folder 12: 5)
  - National Endowment for Democracy, 1990 (Folder 12: 6)
  - PREFACE conference at Wingspread
    - Papers, 1984-1985 (Folder 12: 7)
    - Transcript/record, 1985 (Folder 12: 8)
  - Regional seminars, conference booklets, 1986 (Folder 12: 9-10)
  - Sense of Congress Resolution, 1985-1986 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Strasbourg Conference on Parliamentary Democracy, 1987-1989 (Folder 12: 12-13)
  - Tanguy cocktail party, undated (Folder 13: 1)
  - Truman Institute (Jerusalem), 1986 (Folder 13: 2)
  - United States Information Agency
    - Association of Democracies and International Institute for Democracy, grant proposals, 1986 (Folder 13: 3)
    - Directory of U.S. Organizations Promoting International Democracy, grant and directory, 1989-1991 (Folder 13: 4-5)
    - International Institute of Democracy, grant agreement, 1986 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Labor participants, grant proposal, 1986 (Folder 13: 7)
  - Youth for Democracy, 1989 (Folder 13: 8)
- PREFACE conference at Wingspread, post-conference action file, 1985 (Box 13)
  PREFEACE (Preparatory Meeting for a Conference) was held in 1985 at the Wingspread Conference Center near Racine, Wisconsin. This file includes correspondence, recommendations, proposals, and reports on seminars and groups envisioned at that conference, such as the regional seminars, the All-Democracies Conference, and the Association of Democracies. See also Projects file and Policy matters file.
  - African Regional Seminar, 1985 (Folder 13: 9)
  - All-Democracies Conference, 1985 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Asia-Pacific Regional Seminar, 1985 (Folder 13: 11)
  - Association of Democracies, conference recommendation booklet, 1985 (Folder 13: 12)
  - Caribbean Regional Seminar, 1985 (Folder 13: 13)
  - Distribution of summary report and accompanying correspondence, 1985 (Folder 13: 14)
  - European Regional Seminar, 1985 (Folder 13: 15)
  - International Committee for a Community of Democracies (ICCD), 1985 (Folder 13: 16)
  - Latin American Regional Seminar, 1985 (Folder 13: 17)
  - McFarlane, Robert letter and reply, 1985 (Folder 13: 18)
  - Relations with local embassies and permanent missions to the United Nations, 1985 (Folder 13: 19)
  - Sense of the Congress Resolution, 1985 (Folder 13: 20)
- Funding sources and activities file, 1985-1991 (Box 13-16)
  Includes grants and correspondence with funders and potential donors.
  - General
    - 1986 (Folder 13: 21-22)
    - 1987 (Folder 14: 1-2)
    - 1988 (Folder 14: 3)
    - 1989 (Folder 14: 4)
    - 1990-1991 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Agency for International Development (AID), 1988-1990 (Folder 14: 6-8)
  - All-Democracies Conference
    - Grant proposal and letters, 1986 (Folder 14: 9-10)
    - Grant request to United States Information Agency (USIA), 1988 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Corporate funding appeal, 1988 (Folder 14: 12)
  - C.S. Fund, Maryanne Mott Charitable Trust, 1986 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Esther A. Joseph Klingenstein Fund, 1985-1989 (Folder 14: 14-17)
  - Ford Foundation, 1986, 1988 (Folder 14: 18-19)
  - Friedrich-Naumann-Stiftung, 1987-1988 (Folder 14: 20-21)
  - Grant proposal to Agency for International Development (AID) for African Legal Seminar, 1988 (Folder 14: 22)
  - James S. McDonnell Foundation, 1986 (Folder 14: 23)
  - John M. Olin Foundation, 1985-1987 (Folder 14: 24-25)
  - Joyce Mertz-Gilmore Foundation, 1987 (Folder 14: 26)
  - Letters to foundations and corporations, 1986-1989 (Folder 15: 1-4)
  - Letter to USIA, John Mosher, about AMPARTS Program, 1986 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1985-1987 (Folder 15: 6-7)
  - Lynde and Harry Bradley Foundation, 1986-1987 (Folder 15: 8-9)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1987-1988 (Folder 15: 10-11)
  - National Endowment for Democracy (NED) grant proposal, 1988 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Pew Trust
    Includes documents related to Pew Freedom Trust and challenge grants
    - All-Democracies Conference grant, 1986-1988 (Folder 15: 13-15)
    - African Regional Seminar grant, 1986-1988 (Folder 15: 16-18)
    - J. Howard Pew Freedom Trust, 1985, 1990 (Folder 15: 19-20)
  - Richard Lounsbery Foundation, 1986 (Folder 15: 21)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1985-1986 (Folder 15: 22)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1986 (Folder 15: 23)
  - Samuel Bronfman Foundation, 1988 (Folder 15: 24)
  - Sarah Scaife Foundation, 1987 (Folder 15: 25)
  - Sasakawa Peace Foundation, 1988 (Folder 15: 26)
  - Smith Richardson Foundation, 1985-1986 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Supporting letters by Bud McFarlane and Joe Sisco, 1986 (Folder 16: 2)
  - United States Information Agency
    - General, 1989-1991 (Folder 16: 3-4)
    - Contract documents, 1989 (Folder 16: 5)
    - Core funding and grant requests, 1985-1987 (Folder 16: 6)
    - Grant for International Institute of Democracy workshop, 1986-1988 (Folder 16: 7-8)
    - Grant for Standing Committee of International Institute for Democracy, 1988 (Folder 16: 9)
  - United States Institute for Peace, 1986-1989 (Folder 16: 10-12)
  - W. Alton Jones Foundation, 1986, 1989 (Folder 16: 13-14)
  - Willametta K. Day Foundation, 1986 (Folder 16: 15)
- Public relations and the media file, 1983-1991 (Box 16-17)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, and ICCD newsletters.
  - General
    - 1985-1986 (Folder 16: 16)
    - 1986-1987 (Folder 16: 17)
    - 1988 (Folder 16: 18)
    - 1989 (Folder 17: 1)
    - 1991 (Folder 17: 2)
  - Asia and Pacific, 1986-1987 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Associated Press article, 1986-1987 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Folder 17: 5)
  - The Courier, correspondence and drafts, 1985-1987 (Folder 17: 6-8)
    CCD-USA newsletter
  - Europe, 1987 (Folder 17: 9)
  - ICCD Courier, 1983-1990 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Latin America and Caribbean, 1986 (Folder 17: 11)
  - News conference, 1985 (Folder 17: 12)
  - News release on Haitian situation, 1987 (Folder 17: 13)
  - North America, 1987 (Folder 17: 14)
  - Wall Street Journal article by Samuel De Palma, 1985 (Folder 17: 15)
- Trips and visits file, 1985-1987 (Box 17)
  Includes correspondence, notes and travel arrangements concerning trips of CCD-USA members.
  - De Palma, Samuel, San Francisco, 1986 (Folder 17: 16)
  - De Palma, Samuel and Tom Stern, New York, 1987 (Folder 17: 17)
  - De Palma, Samuel and Charles Tanguy, New York, 1986 (Folder 17: 18)
  - Foulon, Robert, the Pacific, 1985-1986 (Folder 17: 19)
  - Huntley, James, Western Europe, 1987 (Folder 17: 20)
  - Kaufman, Edy, Washington, 1986 (Folder 17: 21)
  - Popper, David and William Steadman, Latin America and Caribbean, 1987 (Folder 17: 22)
  - Stern, Tom, Japan, Australia, and Fiji, 1985 (Folder 17: 23)
- Policy matters file, 1985-1987 (Box 17)
  Includes meeting minutes concerning CCD-USA policy and proposals for the Association of Democracies and the International Institute for Democracy.
  - Association for Democracies, 1985-1986 (Folder 17: 24-25)
  - International Institute for Democracy, 1985-1987 (Folder 17: 26-28)
  - Policy meetings, 1985 (Folder 17: 29-30)
  - "A Political Grand Strategy for the Democracy Initiative", 1985-1986 (Folder 17: 31-32)
  - PREFACE conference at Wingspread, report of section A, B, and C, undated (Folder 17: 33)
- Name lists and individual file, 1985-1991 (Box 18-20)
  Includes correspondence of individuals with CCD-USA members.
  - Biographies, 1985-1986, undated (Folder 18: 1)
  - Name lists, international, 1986, undated (Folder 18: 2)
  - African Regional Seminar, individual files
    - Chona, Mark (Zambia), 1986 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Doumba, Joseph Charles (Cameroon), 1986 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Fall, Abdel Kadir (Senegal), 1986 (Folder 18: 5)
    - Hasani, Hasani (Tanzania), 1986 (Folder 18: 6)
    - Jallow, Hassan (Gambia), 1986 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Jatta, Haji Dembo (Gambia), 1986-1987 (Folder 18: 8)
    - Mkwana, Adam Sapi (Tanzania), 1986 (Folder 18: 9)
    - Moollan, Cassim (Mauritius), 1986 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Muna, Ben (Cameroon), 1986-1990 (Folder 18: 11)
    - Munyama, Bruce (Zambia), 1986 (Folder 18: 12)
    - Mutasa, Didymus (Zimbabwe), 1986 (Folder 18: 13)
    - Ndiaye, Fara (Senegal), 1986 (Folder 18: 14)
    - Nthume, B. C. (Botswana), 1986-1987 (Folder 18: 15)
    - Nyangira, Nicholas (Kenya), 1986-1989 (Folder 18: 16)
    - Odhiambo, Atieno (Kenya), undated (Folder 18: 17)
    - Olson, Clara (Botswana), 1986 (Folder 18: 18)
    - Waruhiu, Rose (Kenya), 1986 (Folder 18: 19)
  - Individual files
    - Ah Koy, James (Fiji), 1985-1986 (Folder 18: 20)
    - Aiazzi, Anton Luigi (Italy), 1985 (Folder 18: 21)